

# Jesse Adametz

Senior Data Engineer at Graphiq. Passion for automation, productivity, elegant design, and craft

jesseadametz@gmail.com

954-775-7232

Santa Barbara, California, US



https://github.com/jadametz



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jesseadametz

# **A**BOUT

DevOps Engineer with a focus on creating repeatable processes and systems that people enjoy using. Over the last 7 years I've honed my skills in Data Engineering, Infrastructure Provisioning, Database Development & Analysis, Automation, and Operations.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Senior Data Engineer II, Graphiq

Jan 2016 - Present ② 6 months

Graphiq is a semantic technology company that instantly delivers deep insights from the world's data. Since 2010, the company has amassed the world's deepest and most interconnected knowledge graph, encompassing 500 collections, 1 billion entities, 250 billion data points and 25 billion curated relationships. At Graphiq I am currently responsible for all offline infrastructure which hosts our ETL Pipeline of recurring jobs and normalization services.

• Principal developer of Data teams Ansible managed AWS infrastructure

#### **Senior Data Engineer**, Graphiq

Jul 2014 - Jan 2016 **②** 1 year 6 months

As a senior member of Graphig's Data team I instantiated best practices and standards around code quality, open source initiatives, build pipelines, and infrastructure management.

- Contributed the pdi-fastjsoninput-plugin to Pentaho's Kettle project
- Became co-chair of the Training & Development committee, responsible for ensuring and coordinating the contined growth of Graphiq's team

## Data Engineer, Graphiq (formerly FindTheBest)

Aug 2013 - Jul 2014 ② 10 months

As an engineering resource for the Product Management team I developed ETL solutions for ingesting new data sources into the Knowledge Graph, allowing the team to expand into more complex and frequently updating data sets.

- Authored and led a 12 week curriculum on Pentaho's Data-Integration (Kettle), which now serves as the foundation of Product Management's onboarding process and enables self-service development of ETL jobs.
- Developed the first iteration of Engineering's ETL Scheduler and Pipeline

#### Data Analyst / SQL Developer, Experian

Jan 2011 - Sep 2013 2 years 8 months

At Experian I was part of the Autocount team of engineers responsible for the reporting (22M Records/Year) of new and used vechile sales within the U.S.

- Developed well structured T-SQL, stored procedures, and SSIS packets to automate and handle all ETL processes
- Refactored monthly ETL processes, decreasing processing time by 25%
- Refined monthly commits to Reporting Warehouse, decreasing data transfer time by 50%

# Setup Configuration Specialist, Aon Hewitt

Reviewed and executed test (including regression) plans in order to solve system defects

### Management Information Systems Intern, Lockheed Martin

Apr 2009 - Aug 2010 **②** 1 year 3 months

As a member of the M-TADS/PNVS Reset team I helped to manage logistics of three program contacts responsible for the maintenance of Apache helicopter systems returning from theater.

Developed and maintained loan tracking database and metrics to ensure contract integrity

# SKILLS

Software Development (master): MySQL (Percona), Pentaho Kettle, Python.

**DevOps (intermediate):** Ansible, AWS, Docker, Jenkins.

### **EDUCATION**

### Mangement Information Systems, Bachelor of Science, University of Central Florida

Jun 2006 - Aug 2010

### Computer Programming & Analysis, Associate of Science, Valencia College

Jan 2012 - Apr 2013

### **A**WARDS

### Winner: Fuelzee, Startup Weekend Orlando

Awarded on: Nov 2012

Fuelzee is like Foursquare for gas stations, but with real-time rewards. We help you find the cheapest gas near you, and give you rewards on things like Snickers, Slurpee's, Slim-Jims, and gas!"

### VOLUNTEER WORK

### Docker Santa Barbara Meetup Organizer, Docker

May 2016 - Present

Organize monthly meetup events to discuss all things Docker.

### Hour of Code Volunteer, Code.org

Dec 2015 - Dec 2015

Worked with a 2nd grade class at Leonora Fillmore Elementary School in Lompoc, CA to introduce them to Computer Science and help with Code.org's interactive learning lessons.